<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on The Gastroenterology Data Sciences Institute</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on The Gastroenterology Data Sciences Institute</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Analytics Training</title>
      <link>/post/dataanalytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/dataanalytics/</guid>
      <description>Reproducible research and audit is an important part of day to day gastroenterology. Automating audit can also provide a huge time saving for units and lend itself well to the quality improvements that units strive for without being burdensome. Unfortunately the tools for reproducible and automated audit and research are beyond the skillset for most clinicians as they are not a standard part of clinical training.
The Institute therefore has two aims for gastroenterological data analytics training:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Set Linkage and Resources</title>
      <link>/post/datasetlinkage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/datasetlinkage/</guid>
      <description>Although the NHS is a National service much electronic data has developed in systems that are not integrated with one another. Consequently there are many datasets in individual fields and departments that cannot be cross-referenced with other datasets because the ability to link data by a common record identifier has not been considered at the inception of the dataset.
With the expansion of elecontric data through, for example, the electronic patient record, there has been an increasing interest in data linkage between separate datasets in order to reach more accurate conclusions with bigger datasets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Data Projects</title>
      <link>/post/posts_details/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/posts_details/</guid>
      <description>There are many clinical questions to answer in gastroenterology using different datasets so software that facilitates this will come is several forms. The solutions for problems will often require collaborative efforts between several developers.
Why open source? One aim of the Institute is to create a platform to encourage the collaboration of developers by open sourcing the software. That is to say allowing team building of non-commercial software solutions. The institute has developed a methodology for the development and validation of software for the analysis of datasets and a pipeline that leads to publication for those who have significantly contributed using the rOpenSci framework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Data Projects</title>
      <link>/post/publicengagement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/publicengagement/</guid>
      <description>A tenet of good software development is that it should be collaborative. There is no better way to facilitate this than by making software open source so that the community can contribute.
The gastroenterology data sciences institute believes that all the software projects developed under its guidance should be open sourced. Most of these, often with explanatory vignettes, can be found on the Institute’s github page and we would encourage you to contribute to all the projects there.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>